MOHAMMAD KHEZRI

UX/UI Designer / Front-End Developer



+1 (832) 4179122



khezri@outlook.com



www.kezri.com



github.com/m-khezri

linkedin.com/in/mohammad-khezri

I consider myself to be a combination of design and technological. I enjoy creating, developing and testing digital products. After several years working in the print design industry, I decided to expand my experience in field of UX/UI and Front-End development. I am so excited to continue to learn and grow in the field of UX/UI and web development.

Experience:

Apprentice UX/UI Designer and Front-End Developer Nashville Software School (12 month part-time evening) | Aug 2018 - Aug 2019

Intensive, hands-on, project-driven software development bootcamp focusing on front-end development and UX/UI fundamentals.

- Hands on application of OOP fundamentals and SOLID principles through group and individual projects reflecting real world business problems
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Built single-page applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript libraries like jQuery and React
- · Task Automation with Grunt: Linting with ESLint, module bundling
- Styled applications with CSS Frameworks Bootstrap and wrote custom styles with SASS

Design

- · Create user stories based on assessment of user experience and workflow
- · Produce visual and interactive design with strategic use of typography, layout, color, motion, and behavior
- · Convey interactive story ideas and complex interactions with wireframes or prototypes
- · Applied corporate style guides and pattern libraries to new applications and web sites
- · Focus on user experience with intentional design around speed, efficiency, and smooth functionality.

IT Help Desk Specialist, Social Media, Online Marketer and Photographer A&A Imports Inc. | 2018 - 2019

Manage and maintain cars inventory, cars photography, IT help desk and online advertising

- Help ensure day-to-day operations of IT Infrastructure.
- Keep tracking of active and sold cars information in shared Excel file
- Implemented remote access for the CEO to review activities in three location
- Tacking pictures of new cars and posting on website and social media
- Support the sales department by posting cars on marketplaces
- · Update and maintain website everyday

Art Director, Senior Graphic Designer and Photographer, 2004-2017 Mazinoor Lighting Industries Inc. | 2004 - 2017

As an art director, was responsible to lead a team of creative to design variety of design materials and web design

- Directed design and led five designers to ensure all projects meet deadlines and design-system.
- · Working closely with ICT department in order to effectively design websites for clients and agencies
- · Worked closely with sales and marketing to understand customer needs and goals in order to plan for advertising effectively
- · Acted as a pre-press color management specialist and supervised offset and digital printing
- Designed and supervised products manual instruction, pricelist booklets, commercial magazines, office stationary, label and package design, convention advertising products, etc., using Adobe Creative Suits on both Mac/ PC platforms
- Videography and project / product photography using full-frame DSLR cameras for 100+ projects
- Project management through ERP system

Skills:

- UX research
- · Usability testing
- User persona
- Wireframes
- · Interactive prototypes
- · Interaction & animation
- · High fidelity visual design
- Illustration
- Icon design
- · Style guides and design systems

Technical:

- · HTML and CSS engineering
- · Less and sass preprocessing
- · Basic JavaScript coding
- Responsive design and development
- Modular component engineering
- · Git and GitHub version control
- · Command line workflow • Node / Grunt / npm

Tools and Apps:

- Adobe Creative Suite, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe XD
- Keynote
- Wireframing tools: Invision, Figma
- VS-cod

Project:

Rhino Splits

github.com/m-khezri/rhino-splits

Research and design an application for online payment among friends for both mobile and web platforms. This application was designed to simplify payment splits among friends so they can make a payment or send reminders. Users can login and setup bank account then either make a payment or send reminder to friends.

Technologies used:















Read more on my website: www.kezri.com

Education:

UX/UI Design for Digital Products Front-End Development Nashville Software School, 2018-2019

Bachelor degree **Graphic Design and Printing** Academy of Art, Babol, Iran, 2008 - 2012